<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Browser Extension on Softorage</title>
    <link>https://softorage.com/categories/browser-extension/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Browser Extension on Softorage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Code licensed under Apache license 2.0. Unless otherwise noted, content licensed under CC-BY-SA-3.0 license.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 18:12:46 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://softorage.com/categories/browser-extension/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RoboForm</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/roboform/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/roboform/</guid>
      <description>RoboForm is a form filler and password manager. Its free version has features such as multi-platform support, unlimited logins, passwords creation, password audit and form filling. Its paid version(s) include features depending on the price paid, such as access on all devices, account data backup, share logins functionality and 24/7 support.
Blog I User Manual I Help Center</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe Flash Player</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/adobe-flash-player/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/adobe-flash-player/</guid>
      <description>Adobe Flash Player (labeled Shockwave Flash in Internet Explorer and Firefox) is computer software for using content created on the Adobe Flash platform, including viewing multimedia contents, executing rich Internet applications, and streaming audio and video. Flash Player can run from a web browser as a browser plug-in or on supported mobile devices. Flash Player runs SWF files that can be created by Adobe Flash Professional, Adobe Flash Builder or by third party tools such as FlashDevelop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>