<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Search on Softorage</title>
    <link>https://softorage.com/search/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Search on Softorage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Code licensed under Apache license 2.0. Unless otherwise noted, content licensed under CC-BY-SA-3.0 license.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 20:53:39 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://softorage.com/search/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scribus</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/scribus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 21:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/scribus/</guid>
      <description>Scribus is an Open Source program that brings professional page layout to Linux, BSD UNIX, Solaris, OpenIndiana, GNU/Hurd, Mac OS X, OS/2 Warp 4, eComStation, and Windows desktops with a combination of press-ready output and new approaches to page design.
Underneath a modern and user-friendly interface, Scribus supports professional desktop publishing features, such as color separations, CMYK and spot colors, ICC color management, and versatile PDF creation.
Books about Scribus are available in several languages, including an official manual for v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FontForge</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/fontforge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 21:24:39 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/fontforge/</guid>
      <description>FontForge is a font editor which supports many common font formats. To facilitate automated format conversion and other repetitive tasks, FontForge implements two scripting languages: its own language and Python. FontForge can run scripts from its GUI, from the command line, and also offers its features as a Python module so it can be integrated into any Python program.
FontForge supports Adobe&amp;rsquo;s OpenType feature file specification (with its own extensions to the syntax).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krita</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/krita/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 21:37:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/krita/</guid>
      <description>Krita is a free-software and an open-source raster graphics editor, designed primarily for digital painting and animation purposes. It features a low-distract UI, high-quality OpenGL accelerated canvas, color management support, advanced brush engine, non-destructive layers and masks, group-based layer management, vector artwork support and switchable customization profiles.
Krita is a FREE and open source painting tool designed for concept artists, illustrators, matte and texture artists, and the VFX industry. Krita has been in development for over 10 years and has had an explosion in growth recently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avast Secure Browser</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/avast-secure-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 20:01:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/avast-secure-browser/</guid>
      <description>Avast Secure Browser is a free Chromium based web browser developed by Avast that focuses on internet security and privacy. Avast Secure Browser was originally called &amp;ldquo;SafeZone&amp;rdquo; before being revamped and rebranded as &amp;lsquo;Avast Secure Browser&amp;rsquo; in early 2018. Before the revamp and rename, SafeZone&amp;rsquo;s design was similar to that of the Opera browser.
It has features such as Ad Block, Bank mode, Passwords, Video downloader, Anti-tracking &amp;amp; Anti-fingerprinting, Anti-fishing, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>darktable</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/darktable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 20:01:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/darktable/</guid>
      <description>darktable is a free and open-source photography workflow application and raw developer. Rather than being a raster graphics editor like Adobe Photoshop or GIMP, it comprises a subset of image editing operations specifically aimed at non-destructive raw photo post-production. It is primarily focused on improving a photographer&amp;rsquo;s workflow by facilitating the handling of large numbers of images.
All editing is fully non-destructive and only operates on cached image buffers for display.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HitFilm Express</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/hitfilm-express/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 20:01:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/hitfilm-express/</guid>
      <description>HitFilm Express is a video editing software with VFX tools to make content, films or gaming videos. It supports MP4 H.264 import &amp;amp; export, AVCHD import, QuickTime import (QuickTime install required on Windows) and AVI, M2T, M2TS, MTS, MXF (DVCPro HD), DV, HDV, WMV video import.
Forum I FAQ I Documentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LibreOffice</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/libreoffice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 20:01:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/libreoffice/</guid>
      <description>LibreOffice is a free and open-source office suite, a project of The Document Foundation. It was forked from OpenOffice.org in 2010, which was an open-sourced version of the earlier StarOffice.
LibreOffice uses the international ISO/IEC standard OpenDocument file format (ODF) as its native format to save documents for all of its applications. LibreOffice also supports the file formats of most other major office suites, including Microsoft Office(.doc, .docx, .xls, .xlsx, .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla Thunderbird</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/mozilla-thunderbird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 20:01:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/mozilla-thunderbird/</guid>
      <description>Thunderbird is an email, news feed, RSS feed, and chat (XMPP, IRC, Twitter) client. Its features include message management; junk filtering; extensions and themes; standards support: POP,IMAP, LDAP, S/MIME, OpenPGP; file formats supported: mbox, maildir; file linking; HTML code insertion; cross-platform support for Linux, macOS, Windows, with unofficial ports for FreeBSD, OpenBSD; localization; and security.
Blog I Forum I Documentation I FAQ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 20:01:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/orange/</guid>
      <description>Orange is a component structured data mining as well as machine learning software suite written in python language. It&amp;rsquo;s a data visualization as well as evaluation software, with regard to novice and experts alike. Data mining can be done via visual programming or even python scripting.
Orange components are called widgets. Widgets cover a wide variety, ranging from simple data visualization, subset selection, and pre-processing, to empirical evaluation of learning algorithms and predictive modeling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Torch</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/torch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 20:01:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/torch/</guid>
      <description>Torch is a scientific computing framework with support for machine learning algorithms. It provides N-dimensional arrays, with support for routines for indexing, slicing, transposing, etc.
Torch puts GPU first. It has an interface to C via LuaJIT, linear algebra &amp;amp; numeric optimization routines, neural network and energy-based models. It is embeddable, with ports to iOS and Android backends.
Documentation I Wiki I Mailing list I Gitter chat</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PDF-XChange Editor</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/pdf-xchange-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 20:16:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/pdf-xchange-editor/</guid>
      <description>PDF-XChange Editor is a free PDF viewer/editor and can create, view, edit, annotate, OCR and digitally sign PDF files. Its OCR process identifies text in documents and uses it to create an invisible text layer that is placed on top of the existing text. It can also be used to convert Microsoft Office documents into PDF, which requires source files to be text-based in order to be converted into editable text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foxit Reader</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/foxit-reader/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 12:50:34 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/foxit-reader/</guid>
      <description>Foxit Reader is a multilingual freemium PDF tool that can view, digitally sign, and print PDF files. Early versions of Foxit Reader were notable for faster startup and small file size. It also integrates with ECMs(Enterprise Content Management) and cloud storage.
Blog I Mobile Forum I Desktop Forum I User Manuals I FAQ Windows I FAQ Mac</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightworks</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/lightworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 18:12:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/lightworks/</guid>
      <description>Lightworks is a non-linear editing system (NLE) for editing and mastering digital video. Its features include relatively simple user interface, multiple effects and multiple output formats (Pro version).
Forum I Documentation I FAQ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RoboForm</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/roboform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 18:12:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/roboform/</guid>
      <description>RoboForm is a form filler and password manager. Its free version has features such as multi-platform support, unlimited logins, passwords creation, password audit and form filling. Its paid version(s) include features depending on the price paid, such as access on all devices, account data backup, share logins functionality and 24/7 support.
Blog I User Manual I Help Center</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KeePass</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/keepass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 20:39:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/keepass/</guid>
      <description>KeePass is a free and open-source password manager primarily for Windows, with official support for macOS and Linux operating systems through the use of Mono. There are also unofficial ports for Windows Phone, Android, iOS, and BlackBerry devices.
It stores usernames, passwords, and other fields, including free-form notes and file attachments, in an encrypted file. This file can be protected by any combination of a master password, a key file, and the current Windows account details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PuTTY</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/putty/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 15:50:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/putty/</guid>
      <description>PuTTY is a free and open-source terminal emulator, serial console and network file transfer application. It is an implementation of SSH and Telnet for Windows and Unix platforms, along with an xterm terminal emulator.
Documentation I Mailing lists I FAQ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WinCDEmu</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/wincdemu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 20:43:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/wincdemu/</guid>
      <description>WinCDEmu is an open-source utility for mounting disk image files in Microsoft Windows. It runs on 32-bit and 64-bit Windows versions from XP to Windows 10; has size less than 2MB; does not occupy drive letters when not used.
Tutorials</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WinSCP</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/winscp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 20:01:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/winscp/</guid>
      <description>WinSCP is a free and open-source SFTP, FTP, WebDAV, Amazon S3 and SCP client for Microsoft Windows. Its main function is file transfer between a local and a remote computer. It uses Secure Shell (SSH) and supports the SCP protocol in addition to SFTP. It also offers scripting and basic file manager functionality.
News I Forum I Documentation I FAQ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyberduck</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/cyberduck/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 22:27:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/cyberduck/</guid>
      <description>Cyberduck is an open source browser client for FTP and SFTP, WebDAV, and cloud storage with support for Amazon S3, OpenStack Swift, Backblaze B2, Microsoft Azure &amp;amp; OneDrive, Google Drive and Dropbox. It supports FTP/TLS (FTP secured over SSL/TLS), using AUTH TLS as well as directory synchronization. It is also able to open some files in external text editors. Cyberduck includes a bookmark manager and supports Apple&amp;rsquo;s Keychain and Bonjour networking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FileZilla</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/filezilla/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 22:27:27 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/filezilla/</guid>
      <description>FileZilla is a free and open source software, cross-platform FTP application, consisting of FileZilla Client and FileZilla Server. Client supports FTP, FTP over TLS (FTPS) and SFTP. FileZilla Server is an FTP and FTPS Server.
Forum I Wiki I Documentation I FAQ I IRC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7-Zip</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/7-zip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/7-zip/</guid>
      <description>7-Zip is a file archiver, file manager developed by Igor Pavlov and was first released in 1999. It includes support for:
 Un/packing: 7z, XZ, BZIP2, GZIP, TAR, ZIP and WIM file formats Unpacking: AR, ARJ, CAB, CHM, CPIO, CramFS, DMG, EXT, FAT, GPT, HFS, IHEX, ISO, LZH, LZMA, MBR, MSI, NSIS, NTFS, QCOW2, RAR, RPM, SquashFS, UDF, UEFI, VDI, VHD, VMDK, WIM, XAR and Z file formats  Its other features include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accord.NET</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/accord.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/accord.net/</guid>
      <description>Accord.NET is a framework for scientific computing in .NET. The framework is comprised of multiple libraries encompassing a wide range of scientific computing applications, such as statistical data processing, machine learning, artificial intelligence, pattern recognition, including but not limited to, computer vision and computer audition. The framework offers a large number of probability distributions, hypothesis tests, kernel functions and support for most popular performance measurements techniques.
The framework comprises a set of libraries that are available in source code as well as via executable installers and NuGet packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe Acrobat DC</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/adobe-acrobat-dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/adobe-acrobat-dc/</guid>
      <description>Adobe Acrobat DC (formerly Acrobat Exchange) is a commercial desktop publishing software that allows to view, print, share, annotate, as well as create, edit, convert, digitally sign, encrypt, export and publish PDF files.
Its features include, edit scanned documents; create protected PDFs; export PDFs to MS Office; fill, sign, and send forms; delete sensitive information; work with Dropbox, Box, Google Drive, and OneDrive.
Blog I Release Notes I Forum | User Guide I FAQ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe Acrobat Reader DC</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/adobe-acrobat-reader-dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/adobe-acrobat-reader-dc/</guid>
      <description>Adobe Acrobat Reader DC (formerly Adobe Reader, Adobe Acrobat Reader) is a freemium document viewer software viewing, printing, signing, sharing, and annotating PDFs. It&amp;rsquo;s a PDF viewer that can open and interact with all types of PDF content – including forms and multimedia. It’s connected to Adobe Document Cloud services, which allows to work with PDFs on any device, from anywhere.
Acrobat Reader DC, has a set of premium features, which are activated on a purchase of subscription to Adobe Acrobat PDF Pack, Adobe Acrobat Export PDF, or Adobe Sign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe Flash Player</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/adobe-flash-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/adobe-flash-player/</guid>
      <description>Adobe Flash Player (labeled Shockwave Flash in Internet Explorer and Firefox) is computer software for using content created on the Adobe Flash platform, including viewing multimedia contents, executing rich Internet applications, and streaming audio and video. Flash Player can run from a web browser as a browser plug-in or on supported mobile devices. Flash Player runs SWF files that can be created by Adobe Flash Professional, Adobe Flash Builder or by third party tools such as FlashDevelop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe Photoshop</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/adobe-photoshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/adobe-photoshop/</guid>
      <description>Adobe Photoshop is a raster graphics editor developed and published by Adobe Inc. It makes use of layering to allow for depth and flexibility in the design and editing process, as well as provide powerful editing tools, that when combined, are capable of just about anything.
Photoshop&amp;rsquo;s naming scheme was initially based on version numbers. However, in October 2002 (following the introduction of Creative Suite branding), each new version of Photoshop was designated with &amp;ldquo;CS&amp;rdquo; plus a number; e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AForge.NET</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/aforge.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/aforge.net/</guid>
      <description>AForge.NET is a computer vision and artificial intelligence library originally developed by Andrew Kirillov for the .NET Framework. The source code and binaries of the project are available under the terms of the Lesser GPL and the GPL (GNU General Public License). Another (unaffiliated) project called Accord.NET was created to extend the features of the original AForge.NET library.
News Archive I Forum I Documentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hadoop</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/apache-hadoop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/apache-hadoop/</guid>
      <description>Apache(TM) Hadoop(R) is a library framework that facilitate using a network of many computers to solve problems involving massive amounts of data and computation providing for distributed storage and processing of big data using the MapReduce programming model.
 It is designed to scale up from single servers to thousands of machines, each offering local computation and storage. Rather than rely on hardware to deliver high-availability, the library itself is designed to detect and handle failures at the application layer, so delivering a highly-available service on top of a cluster of computers, each of which may be prone to failures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Mahout</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/apache-mahout/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/apache-mahout/</guid>
      <description>Apache Mahout(TM) is an open source project that is primarily used for creating scalable machine learning algorithms. It implements machine learning techniques such as, collaborative filtering, clustering, recommendation and classification.
It also provides Java libraries for common math operations (focused on linear algebra and statistics) and primitive Java collections.
A mahout is a word used in South Asian countries to describe one who drives an elephant as its master. The name comes from its close association with Apache Hadoop which uses an elephant as its logo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache MXNet (Incubating)</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/apache-mxnet-incubating/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/apache-mxnet-incubating/</guid>
      <description>Apache MXNet is an open source multi-language machine learning (ML) library especially to train and deploy deep neural networks, on a wide array of devices. Once embedded in the host language, it blends declarative symbolic expression with imperative tensor computation. It is built on a dynamic dependency scheduler that automatically parallelizes both symbolic and imperative operations on the fly. A graph optimization layer on top of that makes symbolic execution fast and memory efficient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Spark</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/apache-spark/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/apache-spark/</guid>
      <description>Apache Spark(TM) is an open-source distributed general-purpose cluster computing framework with (mostly) in-memory data processing engine that can do ETL, analytics, machine learning and graph processing on large volumes of data at rest (batch processing) or in motion (streaming processing) with rich concise high-level APIs for the programming languages: Scala, Python, Java, R, and SQL.
In contrast to Hadoop’s two-stage disk-based MapReduce computation engine, Spark’s multi-stage (mostly) in-memory computing engine allows for running most computations in memory, and hence most of the time provides better performance for certain applications, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache SystemML</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/apache-systemml/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/apache-systemml/</guid>
      <description>Apache SystemML is a machine learning system with support for Java 8+, Scala 2.11+, Python 2.7/3.5+, Hadoop 2.6+, and Spark 2.1+. It provides a workplace for machine learning using big data. As It runs on top of Apache Spark, it automatically scales data, line by line, determining whether the code should be run on the driver or an Apache Spark cluster. Future releases may include additional deep learning with GPU capabilities such as importing and running neural network architectures and pre-trained models for training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ardour</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/ardour/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/ardour/</guid>
      <description>Ardour is a hard disk recorder and digital audio workstation application. It runs on Linux, macOS, FreeBSD and Microsoft Windows. Its primary author is Paul Davis, who is also responsible for the JACK Audio Connection Kit. Ardour is intended to be digital audio workstation software suitable for professional use.
Released under the terms of the GNU General Public License (version two or any later version), Ardour is free software. Users who download from the project&amp;rsquo;s website are asked to pay at least $1 for downloading prebuilt binaries of Ardour; those users then have the right to obtain minor updates until the next major release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art of Illusion</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/art-of-illusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/art-of-illusion/</guid>
      <description>Art of Illusion is a 3D-graphics software, with similar intent of use as for example 3DS-Max or Maya of the commercial software packages or Blender or Wings 3D on the freeware side. Though some sources seem to confuse 3D-modeling with CAD, Art of Illusion does not provide any CAD-features.
Some user reviews describe Art of Illusion as &amp;lsquo;intuitive&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;straight forward to learn&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;good candidate for the first 3D modelling tool&amp;rsquo;, while some characterize it as &amp;lsquo;software for experienced CAD users&amp;rsquo; or taking plenty of time to figure out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atom (Text Editor)</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/atom-text-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/atom-text-editor/</guid>
      <description>Atom is a text editor and source code editor developed by GitHub, with support for plug-ins written in Node.js, and embedded Git Control. It is built with web technologies like HTML, CSS, JavaScript, specifically CoffeeScript and Less. It is based on Electron framework that enables cross-platform desktop applications using Chromium and Node.js.
Atom has installable packages that add extra functionality to it. An example is Teletype, which allows collaborating on code right from the editor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audacity</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/audacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/audacity/</guid>
      <description>Audacity imports sounds and music, puts sound effects against individual tracks and mixes things like music tracks and podcasts together. Audacity comes with many professional editing and recording functions. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to create both live recordings as well as cut tracks. In addition, Audacity has an audio toolbox with countless effects, an equalizer and frequency analysis on board.
Audacity is a digital audio editor with 1500+ stars on GitHub and is present in Software Repositories of major Linux distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avast Antivirus</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/avast-antivirus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/avast-antivirus/</guid>
      <description>Avast Antivirus is a family of internet security applications developed by Avast for Microsoft Windows, macOS, Android and iOS. The Avast Antivirus products include free and proprietary versions that provide computer security, browser security, antivirus software, firewall, anti-phishing, antispyware, and anti-spam among other services.
Blog I Forum I Documentation I FAQ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>balenaEtcher</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/balenaetcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/balenaetcher/</guid>
      <description>Etcher is a OS image flasher built with web technologies, a utility used for writing image files such as .iso and .img files, as well as zipped folders onto storage media to create live SD cards and USB flash drives. It protects from accidentally writing to hard-drives and ensures every byte of data was written correctly. It can flash directly Raspberry Pi devices that support the usbboot protocol.
Etcher was developed using the Electron framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/blender/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/blender/</guid>
      <description>Blender is a professional, free and open-source 3D computer graphics software toolset used for creating animated films, visual effects, art, 3D printed models, interactive 3D applications and video games. Blender&amp;rsquo;s features include 3D modeling, UV unwrapping, texturing, raster graphics editing, rigging and skinning, fluid and smoke simulation, particle simulation, soft body simulation, sculpting, animating, match moving, camera tracking, rendering, motion graphics, video editing and compositing. It also features an integrated game engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brave (Web Browser)</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/brave-web-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/brave-web-browser/</guid>
      <description>Brave is a free and open-source privacy-focused web browser developed by Brave Software, Inc. based on the Chromium web browser. It uses Blink browser engine and V8 JavaScript engine. The browser blocks ads and website trackers, and provides a way for users to send cryptocurrency contributions in the form of Basic Attention Tokens to websites and content creators. It allows users to surf the web using TOR, to protect their privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caffe</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/caffe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/caffe/</guid>
      <description>Caffe (Convolutional Architecture for Fast Feature Embedding) is a deep learning framework, originally developed at University of California, Berkeley.
 Caffe is a deep learning framework made with expression, speed, and modularity in mind. It is developed by Berkeley AI Research (BAIR) and by community contributors. Yangqing Jia created the project during his PhD at UC Berkeley. - Official website
 Caffe allows switching between CPU and GPU by setting a single flag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCleaner</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/ccleaner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/ccleaner/</guid>
      <description>CCleaner is a utility used to clean potentially unwanted files and invalid Windows Registry entries from a computer. It is system optimization, privacy and cleaning tool. It removes unused files from system - temporary files, broken shortcuts, allowing Windows to run faster and freeing up hard disk space, helps you uninstall software and select which programs start with Windows. It cleans traces of online activities such as Internet history. It contains a registry cleaner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chromium (Web Browser)</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/chromium-web-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/chromium-web-browser/</guid>
      <description>Chromium is an open-source web browser project by Google that forms the basis for Google Chrome. While Chrome is based on Chromium, Google also adds a number of proprietary features to Chrome like automatic updates and support for additional video formats. The Chromium source code is also widely used by other parties to create their own browsers, in a similar manner as Google, while others simply build it as-is and release browsers with the Chromium name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAEMON Tools</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/daemon-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/daemon-tools/</guid>
      <description>DAEMON Tools is a virtual drive and optical disc authoring program. It was originally a successor of Generic SafeDisc emulator and incorporated all of its features. It supports image compression, image password protection (to .mds and .mdx images), image creation (supported output formats include .iso, .mds/.mdf and .mdx), along with more advanced features for premium versions such as Pro and Ultra.
Blog I Forum I FAQ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eclipse Deeplearning4j</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/eclipse-deeplearning4j/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/eclipse-deeplearning4j/</guid>
      <description>Eclipse Deeplearning4j is a deep learning programming library written for Java and Scala and a computing framework with wide support for deep learning algorithms.
 There are a lot of knobs to turn when you’re training a distributed deep-learning network. We’ve done our best to explain them, so that Eclipse Deeplearning4j can serve as a DIY tool for Java, Scala and Clojure programmers working on Hadoop and other file systems. - Official website</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ELKI</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/elki/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/elki/</guid>
      <description>ELKI is Environment for Developing KDD(Knowledge Discovery in Databases, &amp;ldquo;Data Mining&amp;quot;)-Applications Supported by Index-Structures.
 ELKI is an open source (AGPLv3) data mining software written in Java. The focus of ELKI is research in algorithms, with an emphasis on unsupervised methods in cluster analysis and outlier detection. In order to achieve high performance and scalability, ELKI offers data index structures such as the R*-tree that can provide major performance gains. ELKI is designed to be easy to extend for researchers and students in this domain, and welcomes contributions of additional methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eM Client</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/em-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/em-client/</guid>
      <description>eM Client is an e-mail client for sending and receiving e-mails, managing calendars, contacts, and tasks. It was developed as a user-friendly alternative to existing e-mail clients and calendar solutions. It supports PGP encryption, backup, table editor, image editing and auto-replies for Gmail. eM Client requires Microsoft .NET Framework 2.0 installation.
Blog I Forum I Documentation - PDF I FAQ I Tutorials</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evince</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/evince/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/evince/</guid>
      <description>Evince is a document viewer for PDF, PostScript, DjVu, TIFF, XPS and DVI formats. It was designed for the GNOME desktop environment. The developers of Evince intended to replace the multiple GNOME document viewers with a single and simple application. The Evince motto sums up the project aim: &amp;ldquo;Simply a Document Viewer&amp;rdquo;. GNOME releases have included Evince since GNOME 2.12 (September 2005). Evince code consists mainly of C, with a small part (the code that interfaces with Poppler) written in C++.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>f.lux</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/f.lux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/f.lux/</guid>
      <description>f.lux is a utility software that adjusts a display&amp;rsquo;s color temperature according to location and time of day. The program is designed to reduce eye strain during night-time use, helping to reduce disruption of sleep patterns.
Blog/News I Forum I FAQ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GIMP</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/gimp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/gimp/</guid>
      <description>GIMP (GNU Image Manipulation Program) is a free and open-source raster graphics editor used for image retouching and editing, free-form drawing, converting between different image formats, and more specialized tasks.
GIMP allows to create images with tools for airbrushing, penciling, cloning, and creating gradients. Power users can create their own brushes and patterns to use later. It also allows users to manipulate images imported into the program, further allowing to crop, add text, resize, and create nested layers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/godot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/godot/</guid>
      <description>Godot is a game engine which was initially developed for several companies in Latin America before its public release. The development environment runs on Windows, macOS, Linux, BSD and Haiku (both 32 and 64-bit) and can create games targeting PC, mobile and web platforms.
The architecture is built around a concept of a tree of nested &amp;ldquo;scenes&amp;rdquo;. All game resources, from scripts to graphical assets, are saved as part of the computer&amp;rsquo;s file system (rather than in a database).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GOM Player</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/gom-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/gom-player/</guid>
      <description>GOM Player is a media player developed by the GOM &amp;amp; Company of South Korea. Its main features include the ability to play some broken media files and find missing codecs using a codec finder service.
FAQ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/google-chrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/google-chrome/</guid>
      <description>The Google Chrome Web browser is based on the open source Chromium project. Google released Chrome in 2008 and issues several updates a year. It is available for Windows, macOS, Linux, Android and iOS operating systems. The Google Chrome browser takes a sandboxing-based approach to Web security. Each open website runs as its own process, which helps prevent malicious code on one page from affecting others (or the computer operating system at large).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hamster Zip Archiver</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/hamster-zip-archiver/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/hamster-zip-archiver/</guid>
      <description>Hamster Zip Archiver is a free file archiver for Windows developed by Hamstersoft, with focus on simplicity and looks. It supports zip, 7z, arj, bz2, tbz, gzip, deb, dmg, img, gz, tgz, hfs, lzh, rmp, pkg, z, taz, cab, iso, rar, tar, wim, swm, jar, along with some other formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HandBrake</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/handbrake/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/handbrake/</guid>
      <description>HandBrake is a free and open-source video transcoder to convert video from one format to another, and to rip CD/DVD to popular video formats. It transcodes video and audio from nearly any format to a handful of modern ones, but it does not defeat or circumvent copy protection. Its developers removed libdvdcss (the open-source library responsible for unscrambling DVDs encrypted with the Content Scramble System (CSS)) from the application in version 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is a static site generator written in Go. It takes data files, i18n bundles, configuration, templates for layouts, static files, and content written in Markdown and renders a static website. Some notable features are multilingual support, image processing, custom output formats, and shortcodes.
News I Forum I Documentation I FAQ I Gitter for Devs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inkscape</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/inkscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/inkscape/</guid>
      <description>Inkscape is professional quality vector graphics editor software which runs on Windows, Mac OS X and GNU/Linux.
Inkscape is widely used for both artistic and technical illustrations such as cartoons, clip art, logos, typography, diagramming and flowcharting. It can import and export various file formats, including SVG, AI, EPS, PDF, PS and PNG. It has a comprehensive feature set, a simple interface, multi-lingual support and is designed to be extensible; users can customize Inkscape&amp;rsquo;s functionality with add-ons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Explorer</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/internet-explorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/internet-explorer/</guid>
      <description>Internet Explorer(since v10) (formerly Microsoft Internet Explorer(v6 &amp;amp; earlier) and Windows Internet Explorer(v7, 8, 9), commonly abbreviated IE or MSIE) is a series of graphical web browsers developed by Microsoft and included in the Microsoft Windows line of operating systems. Internet Explorer was once the most widely used web browser, attaining a peak of about 95% usage share by 2003. It is based on Trident layout engine and Chankra JavaScript engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IObit Driver Booster</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/iobit-driver-booster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/iobit-driver-booster/</guid>
      <description>Driver Booster is a utility designed to update all the obsolete drivers for audio, video, USB or other devices on a PC that may adversely affect the performance of a computer or cause system errors. It allows to search for and identify outdated drivers and to automatically download the missing updates.
It is known for &amp;lsquo;Game Mode&amp;rsquo; setting, which optimizes drivers to improve their performance in games so as to enhance the gaming experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPython</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/ipython/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/ipython/</guid>
      <description>IPython (Interactive Python) is a command shell for interactive computing in multiple programming languages, originally developed for the Python programming language, that offers introspection, rich media, shell syntax, tab completion, and history. IPython provides the following features:
 Interactive shells (terminal and Qt-based) A browser-based notebook interface with support for code, text, mathematical expressions, inline plots and other media Support for interactive data visualization and use of GUI toolkits Flexible, embeddable interpreters to load into one&amp;rsquo;s own projects Tools for parallel computing - Wikipedia   News I Documentation I Mailing list I Wiki I FAQ I Stack Overflow Q&amp;amp;A</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kodi</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/kodi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/kodi/</guid>
      <description>Kodi (formerly XBMC) is a home theater and media player software application developed by the XBMC Foundation, a non-profit technology consortium. It is available for multiple operating-systems and hardware platforms, with a 10-foot user interface for use with televisions and remote controls. It allows users to play and view most streaming media, such as videos, music, podcasts, and videos from the Internet, as well as all common digital media files from local and network storage media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LightBulb</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/lightbulb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/lightbulb/</guid>
      <description>LightBulb is a utility that adjusts screen color temperature based on location and time of the day. It reduces eyestrain which may be produced by staring at a computer screen when working late hours. As the day goes on, it continuously adjusts gamma of the screen display, transitioning the display color temperature from cold blue in the afternoon to warm yellow during the night. Its primary objective is to match the color of the screen to the light sources of your surrounding environment - typically, sunlight during the day and artificial light during the night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LMMS</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/lmms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/lmms/</guid>
      <description>LMMS (formerly Linux MultiMedia Studio) is a free and open source digital audio workstation application program, release under GPL v2 license. It allows music to be produced by arranging samples, synthesizing sounds, playing on a MIDI keyboard and combining the features of trackers and sequencers, when run on appropriate hardware.
It allows users to sequence, compose, mix and automate songs in one interface, note playback via MIDI or typing keyboard, consolidate instrument tracks using Beat+Bassline Editor, fine tune patterns, notes, chords and melodies using Piano Roll Editor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LuaTeX</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/luatex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/luatex/</guid>
      <description>LuaTeX is a TeX-based computer typesetting system which is an extended version of pdfTeX using Lua as an embedded scripting language.
 From the user perspective we have pdfTeX as stable and more or less frozen 8 bit engine, XeTeX as unicode input and font aware engine using libraries for font handling, and LuaTeX as engine that is programmable and delegates as much as possible to Lua, with the objective to keep the core engine lean and mean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MacTeX</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/mactex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/mactex/</guid>
      <description>MacTeX is a redistribution of TeX Live, a typesetting environment. While TeX Live is designed to be cross-platform (running on Unix, macOS, and Windows), MacTeX includes Mac-specific utilities and front-ends. It is also pre-configured to work out-of-the-box with macOS as it provides sensible defaults for configuration options that, in TeX Live, are left up to the user to allow for its cross-platform compatibility. - Wikipedia
 See TeX Live.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MALLET</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/mallet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/mallet/</guid>
      <description>MALLET is MAchine Learning for LanguagE Toolkit.
 MALLET is a Java-based package for statistical natural language processing, document classification, clustering, topic modeling, information extraction, and other machine learning applications to text. - Official website
 MALLET includes tools for document classification, sequence tagging, topic modeling.
 Many of the algorithms in MALLET depend on numerical optimization. MALLET includes an efficient implementation of Limited Memory BFGS, among many other optimization methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malwarebytes</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/malwarebytes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/malwarebytes/</guid>
      <description>Malwarebytes is an antivirus software that scans for and removes malicious software, including rogue security software, adware, and spyware. It scans in batch mode, rather than scanning all files opened, reducing interference if another on-demand anti-malware software is also running on the computer.
The free version can be run manually by the user when desired, whereas the paid version can perform scheduled scans, automatically scan files when opened, block IP addresses of malicious web sites, and scan only those services, programs and device drivers that are currently in use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massive Online Analysis (MOA)</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/massive-online-analysis-moa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/massive-online-analysis-moa/</guid>
      <description>MOA (Massive Online Analysis) is an open source framework for data stream mining including machine learning algorithms such as classification, regression, clustering, outlier detection, concept drift detection and recommender systems and tools for evaluation. MOA is written in Java and relates to WEKA project.
MOA allows to build and run experiments of machine learning or data mining on evolving data streams. It is also possible to use WEKA classifiers from MOA, and MOA classifiers and streams from WEKA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matplotlib</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/matplotlib/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/matplotlib/</guid>
      <description>Matplotlib is a Python 2D plotting library which produces publication quality figures in a variety of hardcopy formats and interactive environments across platforms. Matplotlib can be used in Python scripts, the Python and IPython shells, the Jupyter notebook, web application servers, and four graphical user interface toolkits. &amp;hellip; You can generate plots, histograms, power spectra, bar charts, errorcharts, scatterplots, etc., with just a few lines of code. - Official website</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MediaMonkey</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/mediamonkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/mediamonkey/</guid>
      <description>MediaMonkey is a media player and media library application for organizing and playing audio. It uses SQLite to manage its database. It can be extended to handle video and other media formats, with the help of plugins. Freemium version has features like media management, record &amp;amp; convert, burn, and more of them can be seen here. Premium gold license unlocks additional features such as the ability to have multiple media collections, the ability to organize files automatically, and more can be seen here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/microsoft-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/microsoft-edge/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Edge is a web browser developed by Microsoft. Edge includes integration with Cortana and has extensions hosted on the Microsoft Store. Unlike Internet Explorer, Edge does not support the legacy ActiveX and BHO technologies. Originally built with Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s own EdgeHTML and Chakra engines, in 2019 Edge was rebuilt as a Chromium-based browser, using the Blink and V8 engines. Though, for iOS, Microsoft Edge is based on WebKit. Microsoft released the first Chromium-based Edge version on January 15, 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mlpack</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/mlpack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/mlpack/</guid>
      <description>mlpack is a C++ machine learning library with emphasis on scalability, speed, and ease-of-use. Its aim is to make machine learning possible for novice users by means of a simple, consistent API, while simultaneously exploiting C++ language features to provide maximum performance and maximum flexibility for expert users. This is done by providing a set of command-line executables which can be used as black boxes, and a modular C++ API for expert users and researchers to easily make changes to the internals of the algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla Firefox</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/mozilla-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/mozilla-firefox/</guid>
      <description>Mozilla Firefox (or simply Firefox) is a free and open-source web browser developed by The Mozilla Foundation and its subsidiary, Mozilla Corporation. Firefox is available for Windows, macOS, Linux, BSD illumos and Solaris operating systems. Its sibling, Firefox for Android, is also available. Firefox uses the Gecko layout engine to render web pages, which implements current and anticipated web standards. In 2017, Firefox began incorporating new technology under the code name Quantum to promote parallelism and a more intuitive user interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MusicBrainz Picard</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/musicbrainz-picard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/musicbrainz-picard/</guid>
      <description>MusicBrainz Picard is a free and open-source tag editor for identifying, tagging, and organizing digital audio recordings.
It allows to clean local musics and songs by automatically updating artist, album, track information and album art cover for each song.
MusicBrainz is an open source database of music. The MusicBrainz Picard tool uses this database to identify and tag a song. It checks the songs against the MusicBrainz database to see if it can find a match.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notepad&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/notepad&#43;&#43;/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/notepad&#43;&#43;/</guid>
      <description>Notepad++ is a free source code editor and Notepad replacement that supports several languages. Based on the editing component Scintilla, it is written in C++ and uses pure Win32 API and STL to provide higher execution speed and smaller program size.
Its features include:
 Syntax Highlighting and Folding User Defined Syntax Highlighting and Folding Customizable GUI Word completion, Function completion and Function parameters hint Tab interface Document Map  News I Forum I Gitter Chat I User Manual</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NumPy</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/numpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/numpy/</guid>
      <description>NumPy is a library for the Python programming language, adding support for large, multi-dimensional arrays and matrices, along with a large collection of high-level mathematical functions to operate on these arrays.
 NumPy is the fundamental package for scientific computing with Python. It contains among other things:
 a powerful N-dimensional array object sophisticated (broadcasting) functions tools for integrating C/C++ and Fortran code useful linear algebra, Fourier transform, and random number capabilities  Besides its obvious scientific uses, NumPy can also be used as an efficient multi-dimensional container of generic data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenCog</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/opencog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/opencog/</guid>
      <description>OpenCog is a project that aims to build an open source artificial intelligence framework. OpenCog Prime is an architecture for robot and virtual embodied cognition that defines a set of interacting components designed to give rise to human-equivalent artificial general intelligence (AGI) as an emergent phenomenon of the whole system. OpenCog Prime&amp;rsquo;s design is primarily the work of Ben Goertzel while the OpenCog framework is intended as a generic framework for broad-based AGI research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/opencv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/opencv/</guid>
      <description>OpenCV (Open Source Computer Vision Library) is an open source computer vision and machine learning software library. OpenCV was built to provide a common infrastructure for computer vision applications and to accelerate the use of machine perception in the commercial products.
 It has C++, Python and Java interfaces and supports Windows, Linux, Mac OS, iOS and Android. OpenCV was designed for computational efficiency and with a strong focus on real-time applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenNN</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/opennn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/opennn/</guid>
      <description>OpenNN (Open Neural Networks Library) implements neural networks, a main area of deep learning research.
OpenNN implements data mining methods as a bundle of functions. It allows embedding functions in other software tools using an &amp;lsquo;Application Programming Interface (API)&amp;rsquo; for the interaction between the software tool and the predictive analytics tasks. A graphical user interface (GUI) is still missing, but some functions can support the integration of specific visualization tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pandas</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/pandas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/pandas/</guid>
      <description>pandas is a software library written for the Python programming language for data manipulation and analysis. In particular, it offers data structures and operations for manipulating numerical tables and time series. - Wikipedia
 Documentation I Stack Overflow Q&amp;amp;A I Mailing list - Developers I FAQ I IRC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PeaZip</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/peazip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/peazip/</guid>
      <description>PeaZip is free file archiver utility, based on Open Source technologies of 7-Zip, p7zip, Brotli, FreeArc, PAQ, Zstandard, and PEA projects. PeaZip works as a compression and encryption utility. It can open extract 180+ archive formats; full list can be found here.
News I Forum/Tickets I Wiki I Online Tutorials I FAQ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psiphon</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/psiphon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/psiphon/</guid>
      <description>Psiphon is an open-source relay-based internet censorship circumvention tool utilizing a combination of secure communication and obfuscation technologies. It is a centrally managed, and geographically diverse network of thousands of proxy servers, using a performance-oriented, single and multi hop architecture.
In 2014, maliciously repackaged psiphon was found.
Blog I User Guide I FAQ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>qBittorrent</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/qbittorrent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/qbittorrent/</guid>
      <description>qBittorrent is a cross-platform free and open-source BitTorrent client.
Its features include:
 Polished µTorrent-like User Interface No Ads Well-integrated and extensible Search Engine  Simultaneous search in many Torrent search sites Category-specific search requests (e.g. Books, Music, Software)   RSS feed support with advanced download filters (incl. regex) Multiple BitTorrent extensions supported:  Magnet links Distributed hash table (DHT), peer exchange protocol (PEX), local peer discovery (LSD) Private torrents Encrypted connections   Remote control through Web user interface, written with AJAX  Nearly identical to the regular GUI   Sequential downloading (Download in order) Advanced control over torrents, trackers and peers  Torrents queueing and prioritizing Torrent content selection and prioritizing   Bandwidth scheduler Torrent creation tool IP Filtering (eMule &amp;amp; PeerGuardian format compatible) IPv6 compliant UPnP / NAT-PMP port forwarding support Cross-platform: Windows, Linux, macOS, FreeBSD, OS/2 Available in ~70 languages  News I Forum I Wiki I FAQ I IRC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recuva</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/recuva/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/recuva/</guid>
      <description>Recuva is a data recovery and an undeletion program for Windows, developed by Piriform. It is able to undelete files that have been marked as deleted (the operating system marks the areas of the disk in which deleted files were stored as free space). It can recover files deleted from internal and external hard disk drives, USB flash drives, memory cards, portable media players or all random-access storage mediums with a supported file system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rufus</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/rufus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/rufus/</guid>
      <description>Rufus is a free and open-source portable application developed by Pete Batard of Akeo Consulting for Microsoft Windows that can be used to format and create bootable USB flash drives or Live USBs.
Rufus supports a variety of bootable .iso files, including various Linux distributions and Windows installation .iso files, as well as raw disk image files (including compressed ones). If needed, it can install a bootloader such as SYSLINUX or GRUB onto the flash drive to render it bootable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scikit-learn</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/scikit-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/scikit-learn/</guid>
      <description>scikit-learn is an open source machine learning library featuring classification, regression, clustering, dimensionality reduction, model selection and preprocessing. It has tools for data mining and data analysis, and is built on NumPy, SciPy, and matplotlib.
As per official website, it features:
 Classification : Identifying to which category an object belongs to Regression : Predicting a continuous-valued attribute associated with an object Clustering : Automatic grouping of similar objects into sets Dimensionality reduction : Reducing the number of random variables to consider Model selection : Comparing, validating and choosing parameters and models Preprocessing : Feature extraction and normalization  Documentation I Wiki I Mailing list I Stack Overflow I FAQ I IRC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SciPy (library)</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/scipy-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/scipy-library/</guid>
      <description>SciPy a free and open-source Python library used for scientific computing and technical computing.
 The SciPy library is one of the core packages that make up the SciPy stack. It provides many user-friendly and efficient numerical routines such as routines for numerical integration and optimization. - Official website
  SciPy refers to several related but distinct entities: * The SciPy ecosystem, a collection of open source software for scientific computing in Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shotcut</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/shotcut/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/shotcut/</guid>
      <description>Shotcut is a free and open-source cross-platform video editing application, developed on the MLT Multimedia Framework. It supports video, audio, and image formats via FFmpeg, and uses a timeline for non-linear video editing of multiple tracks that may be composed of various file formats.
Blog/News I Forum I Tutorials I How-tos I FAQ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sumatra PDF</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/sumatra-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/sumatra-pdf/</guid>
      <description>Sumatra is a document viewer for Windows with support for PDF, eBook (ePub, Mobi), XPS, DjVu, CHM, Comic Book (CBZ and CBR). It is considered to be a lightweight and portable alternative to Adobe Reader.
Forum I News I Documentation I Manual</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SymPy</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/sympy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/sympy/</guid>
      <description>SymPy is a Python library for symbolic mathematics. It aims to become a full-featured computer algebra system (CAS) while keeping the code as simple as possible in order to be comprehensible and easily extensible. SymPy is written entirely in Python. - Official website
 Documentation I Wiki I Mailing list I Gitter chat I IRC I Planet SymPy I FAQ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamViewer</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/teamviewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/teamviewer/</guid>
      <description>TeamViewer is a proprietary software application for remote control, desktop sharing, online meetings, web conferencing and file transfer between computers. It allows remote access to computers or mobile devices and use them as though user were there. It allows to remotely connect to servers, commercial-grade machines, and IoT devices through TeamViewer&amp;rsquo;s global remote access network. TeamViewer includes encryption based on 2048-bit RSA private/public key exchange and AES (256-bit) session encryption, two-factor authentication, enforced password reset on unusual activity and a listing feature for trusted devices (Whitelisting).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TensorFlow</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/tensorflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/tensorflow/</guid>
      <description>TensorFlow is an open source software library for high performance numerical computation. Its flexible architecture allows easy deployment of computation across a variety of platforms (CPUs, GPUs, TPUs), and from desktops to clusters of servers to mobile and edge devices.
TensorFlow was originally developed by researchers and engineers from the Google Brain team within Google’s AI organization.
It comes with strong support for machine learning and deep learning and the flexible numerical computation core is used across many other scientific domains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeraCopy</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/teracopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/teracopy/</guid>
      <description>TeraCopy is a file transfer utility developed by Code Sector, designed as an alternative for the built-in Windows Explorer file transfer feature, with focus on data integrity, file transfer reliability and the ability to pause or resume file transfers.
Blog I User Manual I FAQ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TestDisk</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/testdisk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/testdisk/</guid>
      <description>TestDisk is an open source data recovery utility that runs exclusively from the command-line interface and allows users to check and undelete partitions from a given disk drive. It is primarily designed to help recover lost data storage partitions and/or make non-booting disks bootable again; when these symptoms are caused by faulty software, certain types of viruses or human error (such as accidentally erasing a partition table). It can also be used to collect detailed information about a corrupted drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeX Live</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/tex-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/tex-live/</guid>
      <description>TeX Live is a free software distribution for the TeX typesetting system that includes major TeX-related programs, macro packages, and fonts. It is the replacement of its no-longer supported counterpart teTeX.
 TeX Live is an easy way to get up and running with the TeX document production system. It provides a comprehensive TeX system with binaries for most flavors of Unix, including GNU/Linux, and also Windows. It includes all the major TeX-related programs, macro packages, and fonts that are free software, including support for many languages around the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeXworks</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/texworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/texworks/</guid>
      <description>TeXworks is free and open-source TeX editor, available for Windows, Linux and OS X, released under GPL v2.
 It is a Qt-based graphical user interface to the TeX typesetting system and its LaTeX, ConTeXt, and XeTeX extensions. TeXworks is targeted at direct generation of PDF output. It has a built-in PDF viewer using the poppler library; the viewer has auto-refresh capability, and also features SyncTeX support (which allows the user to synchronize the PDF viewer position with the source, and vice versa with a single click).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Microsoft Cognitive Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/the-microsoft-cognitive-toolkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/the-microsoft-cognitive-toolkit/</guid>
      <description>The Microsoft Cognitive Toolkit—previously known as CNTK—is an open-source toolkit for commercial-grade distributed deep learning. It describes neural networks as a series of computational steps via a directed graph.
The Microsoft Cognitive Toolkit enables to leverage the information within massive data-sets through deep learning by providing scaling, speed, and accuracy with commercial-grade quality and compatibility with the programming languages and algorithms already in use.
News I Documentation I FAQ I Blog</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UC Browser</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/uc-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/uc-browser/</guid>
      <description>UC Browser is a web browser developed by the Singapore/China-based mobile Internet company UCWeb, which is in turn owned by the Alibaba Group. It uses Chromium browser as its base. It is more popular than Google Chrome in some of Asia&amp;rsquo;s fastest-growing markets like India and Indonesia.
The browser uses cloud acceleration and data compression technology. UC Browser&amp;rsquo;s servers act as a proxy which compresses and renders web pages before sending them to users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>uTorrent</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/utorrent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/utorrent/</guid>
      <description>uTorrent is an efficient BitTorrent client from the originator of the BitTorrent protocol. Most of the features present in other BitTorrent clients are present in uTorrent, including bandwidth prioritization, scheduling, RSS auto-downloading, and Mainline DHT. Additionally, uTorrent supports the protocol encryption joint specification and peer exchange.
uTorrent claims to not eat away at valuable system resources; the program typically runs on approx. 6MB of memory.
Blog I Forum I Help I documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vivaldi (Web Browser)</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/vivaldi-web-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/vivaldi-web-browser/</guid>
      <description>Vivaldi is a freeware, cross-platform web browser developed by Vivaldi Technologies, a company founded by Opera Software co-founder and former CEO Jon Stephenson von Tetzchner and Tatsuki Tomita. It is based on Chromium web browser, which uses Blink browser engine and V8 JavaScript engine. It is available for general users but is primarily targeted towards technically-inclined users as well as former Opera users disgruntled by its transition from the Presto layout engine to a Chromium-based browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VLC Media Player</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/vlc-media-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/vlc-media-player/</guid>
      <description>VLC is a free and open source cross-platform multimedia player and framework, developed by the VideoLAN project, that plays most multimedia files as well as DVDs, Audio CDs, VCDs, and various streaming protocols. It can read a large number of popular video and audio formats, such as MPEG, MKV, MP4, MOV, WMV, H.264, WAV, FLV, AVI, etc. It can also convert media into many of the same formats that it is able to read, including the MPEG, ASF, AAC, and MP3 formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebTorrent</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/webtorrent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/webtorrent/</guid>
      <description>WebTorrent is a peer-to-peer (P2P) streaming torrent client written in JavaScript by Feross Aboukhadijeh. WebTorrent uses the same protocol as BitTorrent but uses a different transport. WebTorrent primarily relies on WebRTC connections, while BitTorrent uses TCP connections and UDP datagrams directly.
Dev Documentation I FAQ I IRC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weka</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/weka/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/weka/</guid>
      <description>Weka is a collection of machine learning algorithms for data mining tasks. It contains tools for data preparation, classification, regression, clustering, association rules mining, and visualization. - Official website
 Weka(Waikato Environment for Knowledge Analysis) provides access to deep learning with WekaDeeplearning4j which uses Deeplearning4j.
Blog I New Forum I Old Forum I Documentation I Stack Overflow Q&amp;amp;A I Mailing list I Wiki I FAQ I IRC I SourceForge I Package metadata</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wings 3D</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/wings-3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/wings-3d/</guid>
      <description>Wings 3D is a tool specifically designed to import and modify models through subdivision - a polygonal modeling technique that allows very well-defined polygons.
The program itself does not include tools to create it&amp;rsquo;s own from scratch. Basically, Wings 3D can import models created by other design environments into polygonal meshes and then develop them through subdivision polygons. It also includes a series of tools that will help you allocate materials, textures and UV coordinates to your models, add lights to the scene and perform screenshots among other possibilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WinRAR</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/winrar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/winrar/</guid>
      <description>WinRAR is an archive manager for backing up data and reducing the size of e-mail attachments. Decompress files downloaded from the internet and create new archives in RAR and ZIP file format. Support is provided for RAR, ZIP, CAB, ARJ, LZH, ACE, TAR, GZip, UUE, ISO, BZIP2, Z and 7-Zip file formats.
WinRAR recognises and selects the best compression method for decompressing multi-media files; the compression algorithm compresses multi-media files, executables and object libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XeTeX</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/xetex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/xetex/</guid>
      <description>XeTeX is a TeX typesetting engine using Unicode and supporting modern font technologies such as OpenType, Graphite and Apple Advanced Typography (AAT). - Wikipedia
  XƎTEX is an extension of TEX that integrates TEX&amp;rsquo;s typesetting capabilities with (a) the Unicode text encoding standard (supporting most of the world’s scripts) and (b) modern font technologies (TrueType and OpenType) and text layout services (AAT, OpenType layout, SIL Graphite) provided by the host operating system and available libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xpdf</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/xpdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/xpdf/</guid>
      <description>Xpdf is a free and open-source PDF document viewer for operating systems supported by the Qt toolkit. Versions prior to 4.00 were written for the X Window System and Motif.
Xpdf runs on nearly any Unix-like operating system, but binaries are also available for Windows. Xpdf can decode LZW and read encrypted PDFs. The official version obeys the DRM restrictions of PDF files, which can prevent copying, printing, or converting some PDF files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yooreeka</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/yooreeka/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/yooreeka/</guid>
      <description>Yooreeka is a library for data mining, machine learning, soft computing, and mathematical analysis. It also provides examples.
Google Code I Archive</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opera (Web Browser)</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/opera-web-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 16:58:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/opera-web-browser/</guid>
      <description>Opera is a freeware web browser developed by Opera Software. Opera is a Chromium-based browser using the Blink layout engine.
Opera was conceived at Telenor as a research project in 1994 and was bought by Opera Software in 1995. It was a commercial software for the first ten years and had its own proprietary Presto layout engine. The Presto versions of Opera received many awards, but Presto development ended after a milestone transition to Chromium in 2013.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyTorch</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/pytorch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 16:58:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/pytorch/</guid>
      <description>PyTorch is an open-source machine learning library for Python, based on Torch, used for applications such as natural language processing. One can also reuse Python packages such as NumPy, SciPy and Cython to extend PyTorch when needed.
 PyTorch provides two high-level features:
 Tensor computation (like NumPy) with strong GPU acceleration Deep neural networks built on a tape-based autodiff system - README.md on GitHub repo    Automatic differentiation is done with a tape-based system at both a functional and neural network layer level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity (Game Engine)</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/unity-game-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 16:58:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/unity-game-engine/</guid>
      <description>Unity is a cross-platform game engine developed by Unity Technologies. The engine can be used to create three-dimensional, two-dimensional, virtual reality, and augmented reality games, as well as simulations and other experiences.
Unity has free and paid licensing options. The free license is for personal use or smaller companies generating less than $100,000 annually, and the subscriptions are based on revenues generated by the games using Unity.
Blog I Forum I Devs Q&amp;amp;A I Wiki I Documentation/Manual I Knowledge base/Support I Issue tracker I FAQ I IRC</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>