<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Desktop Publishing on Softorage</title>
    <link>https://softorage.com/categories/desktop-publishing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Desktop Publishing on Softorage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Code licensed under Apache license 2.0. Unless otherwise noted, content licensed under CC-BY-SA-3.0 license.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 21:19:31 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://softorage.com/categories/desktop-publishing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scribus</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/scribus/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/scribus/</guid>
      <description>Scribus is an Open Source program that brings professional page layout to Linux, BSD UNIX, Solaris, OpenIndiana, GNU/Hurd, Mac OS X, OS/2 Warp 4, eComStation, and Windows desktops with a combination of press-ready output and new approaches to page design.
Underneath a modern and user-friendly interface, Scribus supports professional desktop publishing features, such as color separations, CMYK and spot colors, ICC color management, and versatile PDF creation.
Books about Scribus are available in several languages, including an official manual for v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PDF-XChange Editor</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/pdf-xchange-editor/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/pdf-xchange-editor/</guid>
      <description>PDF-XChange Editor is a free PDF viewer/editor and can create, view, edit, annotate, OCR and digitally sign PDF files. Its OCR process identifies text in documents and uses it to create an invisible text layer that is placed on top of the existing text. It can also be used to convert Microsoft Office documents into PDF, which requires source files to be text-based in order to be converted into editable text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foxit Reader</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/foxit-reader/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/foxit-reader/</guid>
      <description>Foxit Reader is a multilingual freemium PDF tool that can view, digitally sign, and print PDF files. Early versions of Foxit Reader were notable for faster startup and small file size. It also integrates with ECMs(Enterprise Content Management) and cloud storage.
Blog I Mobile Forum I Desktop Forum I User Manuals I FAQ Windows I FAQ Mac</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe Acrobat DC</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/adobe-acrobat-dc/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/adobe-acrobat-dc/</guid>
      <description>Adobe Acrobat DC (formerly Acrobat Exchange) is a commercial desktop publishing software that allows to view, print, share, annotate, as well as create, edit, convert, digitally sign, encrypt, export and publish PDF files.
Its features include, edit scanned documents; create protected PDFs; export PDFs to MS Office; fill, sign, and send forms; delete sensitive information; work with Dropbox, Box, Google Drive, and OneDrive.
Blog I Release Notes I Forum | User Guide I FAQ</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>