<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on Softorage</title>
    <link>https://softorage.com/categories/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on Softorage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Code licensed under Apache license 2.0. Unless otherwise noted, content licensed under CC-BY-SA-3.0 license.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://softorage.com/categories/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Avast Antivirus</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/avast-antivirus/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/avast-antivirus/</guid>
      <description>Avast Antivirus is a family of internet security applications developed by Avast for Microsoft Windows, macOS, Android and iOS. The Avast Antivirus products include free and proprietary versions that provide computer security, browser security, antivirus software, firewall, anti-phishing, antispyware, and anti-spam among other services.
Blog I Forum I Documentation I FAQ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malwarebytes</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/malwarebytes/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/malwarebytes/</guid>
      <description>Malwarebytes is an antivirus software that scans for and removes malicious software, including rogue security software, adware, and spyware. It scans in batch mode, rather than scanning all files opened, reducing interference if another on-demand anti-malware software is also running on the computer.
The free version can be run manually by the user when desired, whereas the paid version can perform scheduled scans, automatically scan files when opened, block IP addresses of malicious web sites, and scan only those services, programs and device drivers that are currently in use.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>