<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Game Engine on Softorage</title>
    <link>https://softorage.com/categories/game-engine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Game Engine on Softorage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Code licensed under Apache license 2.0. Unless otherwise noted, content licensed under CC-BY-SA-3.0 license.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://softorage.com/categories/game-engine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/godot/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/godot/</guid>
      <description>Godot is a game engine which was initially developed for several companies in Latin America before its public release. The development environment runs on Windows, macOS, Linux, BSD and Haiku (both 32 and 64-bit) and can create games targeting PC, mobile and web platforms.
The architecture is built around a concept of a tree of nested &amp;ldquo;scenes&amp;rdquo;. All game resources, from scripts to graphical assets, are saved as part of the computer&amp;rsquo;s file system (rather than in a database).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity (Game Engine)</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/unity-game-engine/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/unity-game-engine/</guid>
      <description>Unity is a cross-platform game engine developed by Unity Technologies. The engine can be used to create three-dimensional, two-dimensional, virtual reality, and augmented reality games, as well as simulations and other experiences.
Unity has free and paid licensing options. The free license is for personal use or smaller companies generating less than $100,000 annually, and the subscriptions are based on revenues generated by the games using Unity.
Blog I Forum I Devs Q&amp;amp;A I Wiki I Documentation/Manual I Knowledge base/Support I Issue tracker I FAQ I IRC</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>