<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web Browser on Softorage</title>
    <link>https://softorage.com/categories/web-browser/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web Browser on Softorage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Code licensed under Apache license 2.0. Unless otherwise noted, content licensed under CC-BY-SA-3.0 license.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 20:01:07 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://softorage.com/categories/web-browser/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Avast Secure Browser</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/avast-secure-browser/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/avast-secure-browser/</guid>
      <description>Avast Secure Browser is a free Chromium based web browser developed by Avast that focuses on internet security and privacy. Avast Secure Browser was originally called &amp;ldquo;SafeZone&amp;rdquo; before being revamped and rebranded as &amp;lsquo;Avast Secure Browser&amp;rsquo; in early 2018. Before the revamp and rename, SafeZone&amp;rsquo;s design was similar to that of the Opera browser.
It has features such as Ad Block, Bank mode, Passwords, Video downloader, Anti-tracking &amp;amp; Anti-fingerprinting, Anti-fishing, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brave (Web Browser)</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/brave-web-browser/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/brave-web-browser/</guid>
      <description>Brave is a free and open-source privacy-focused web browser developed by Brave Software, Inc. based on the Chromium web browser. It uses Blink browser engine and V8 JavaScript engine. The browser blocks ads and website trackers, and provides a way for users to send cryptocurrency contributions in the form of Basic Attention Tokens to websites and content creators. It allows users to surf the web using TOR, to protect their privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chromium (Web Browser)</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/chromium-web-browser/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/chromium-web-browser/</guid>
      <description>Chromium is an open-source web browser project by Google that forms the basis for Google Chrome. While Chrome is based on Chromium, Google also adds a number of proprietary features to Chrome like automatic updates and support for additional video formats. The Chromium source code is also widely used by other parties to create their own browsers, in a similar manner as Google, while others simply build it as-is and release browsers with the Chromium name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/google-chrome/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/google-chrome/</guid>
      <description>The Google Chrome Web browser is based on the open source Chromium project. Google released Chrome in 2008 and issues several updates a year. It is available for Windows, macOS, Linux, Android and iOS operating systems. The Google Chrome browser takes a sandboxing-based approach to Web security. Each open website runs as its own process, which helps prevent malicious code on one page from affecting others (or the computer operating system at large).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Explorer</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/internet-explorer/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/internet-explorer/</guid>
      <description>Internet Explorer(since v10) (formerly Microsoft Internet Explorer(v6 &amp;amp; earlier) and Windows Internet Explorer(v7, 8, 9), commonly abbreviated IE or MSIE) is a series of graphical web browsers developed by Microsoft and included in the Microsoft Windows line of operating systems. Internet Explorer was once the most widely used web browser, attaining a peak of about 95% usage share by 2003. It is based on Trident layout engine and Chankra JavaScript engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/microsoft-edge/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/microsoft-edge/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Edge is a web browser developed by Microsoft. Edge includes integration with Cortana and has extensions hosted on the Microsoft Store. Unlike Internet Explorer, Edge does not support the legacy ActiveX and BHO technologies. Originally built with Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s own EdgeHTML and Chakra engines, in 2019 Edge was rebuilt as a Chromium-based browser, using the Blink and V8 engines. Though, for iOS, Microsoft Edge is based on WebKit. Microsoft released the first Chromium-based Edge version on January 15, 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla Firefox</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/mozilla-firefox/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/mozilla-firefox/</guid>
      <description>Mozilla Firefox (or simply Firefox) is a free and open-source web browser developed by The Mozilla Foundation and its subsidiary, Mozilla Corporation. Firefox is available for Windows, macOS, Linux, BSD illumos and Solaris operating systems. Its sibling, Firefox for Android, is also available. Firefox uses the Gecko layout engine to render web pages, which implements current and anticipated web standards. In 2017, Firefox began incorporating new technology under the code name Quantum to promote parallelism and a more intuitive user interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UC Browser</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/uc-browser/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/uc-browser/</guid>
      <description>UC Browser is a web browser developed by the Singapore/China-based mobile Internet company UCWeb, which is in turn owned by the Alibaba Group. It uses Chromium browser as its base. It is more popular than Google Chrome in some of Asia&amp;rsquo;s fastest-growing markets like India and Indonesia.
The browser uses cloud acceleration and data compression technology. UC Browser&amp;rsquo;s servers act as a proxy which compresses and renders web pages before sending them to users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vivaldi (Web Browser)</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/vivaldi-web-browser/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/vivaldi-web-browser/</guid>
      <description>Vivaldi is a freeware, cross-platform web browser developed by Vivaldi Technologies, a company founded by Opera Software co-founder and former CEO Jon Stephenson von Tetzchner and Tatsuki Tomita. It is based on Chromium web browser, which uses Blink browser engine and V8 JavaScript engine. It is available for general users but is primarily targeted towards technically-inclined users as well as former Opera users disgruntled by its transition from the Presto layout engine to a Chromium-based browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opera (Web Browser)</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/opera-web-browser/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/opera-web-browser/</guid>
      <description>Opera is a freeware web browser developed by Opera Software. Opera is a Chromium-based browser using the Blink layout engine.
Opera was conceived at Telenor as a research project in 1994 and was bought by Opera Software in 1995. It was a commercial software for the first ten years and had its own proprietary Presto layout engine. The Presto versions of Opera received many awards, but Presto development ended after a milestone transition to Chromium in 2013.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>