<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scientific Computing on Softorage</title>
    <link>https://softorage.com/categories/scientific-computing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scientific Computing on Softorage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Code licensed under Apache license 2.0. Unless otherwise noted, content licensed under CC-BY-SA-3.0 license.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:10:20 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://softorage.com/categories/scientific-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NumPy</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/numpy/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/numpy/</guid>
      <description>NumPy is a library for the Python programming language, adding support for large, multi-dimensional arrays and matrices, along with a large collection of high-level mathematical functions to operate on these arrays.
 NumPy is the fundamental package for scientific computing with Python. It contains among other things:
 a powerful N-dimensional array object sophisticated (broadcasting) functions tools for integrating C/C++ and Fortran code useful linear algebra, Fourier transform, and random number capabilities  Besides its obvious scientific uses, NumPy can also be used as an efficient multi-dimensional container of generic data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SciPy (library)</title>
      <link>https://softorage.com/software/scipy-library/</link>
      <author>contact@softorage.com (Sanmay Joshi and Softorage contributors)</author>
      <guid>https://softorage.com/software/scipy-library/</guid>
      <description>SciPy a free and open-source Python library used for scientific computing and technical computing.
 The SciPy library is one of the core packages that make up the SciPy stack. It provides many user-friendly and efficient numerical routines such as routines for numerical integration and optimization. - Official website
  SciPy refers to several related but distinct entities: * The SciPy ecosystem, a collection of open source software for scientific computing in Python.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>